Suryaprakash Pal

Indore, Madhya Pradesh suryaprakashpal9_hmi@indeedemail.com 8889115933

An Enthusiastic and Diligent professional, a Red hat and Cisco Certified Engineer working on creating, managing and Developing LINUX servers. Have total 6 years of experience in Technical and Non technical fields.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

Linux Support & Network engineer

DAVV University Indore March 2019 to Present

Configuration and Management of Web servers Apache (http, https) DHCP server, DNS server, Samba server.•

- · Configuration and Management of LVM. ·
- Installation and configuration of LAMP on Centos.
- Installation, configuration and Management of Xen server with Cirtix Application (Learning)•
- Installation and Management of KVM Virtual machine. •
- Taking Backup on Daily basis via RSync and Tar in incremental Basis •
- Backup and Restoration files. •
- Installation and Managing of Ansible and Ansible Playbook files to Create Automation environment. •
- Installing software in Linux. •
- Upgrading and Updating Servers on Daily Basis.•
- Working on AWS for learning CLOUD••
- Configuration and Management of Mysql server
- Configuration and Management of HP Aruba switches 2530 Digisol D-link, (L2 & L3) 2530.•
- Switching (VLAN/ Trunking/ STP) •

IT Support

Nesit Ltd

December 2018 to March 2019

- Troubleshoot and manage network problems
- Check PC configuration for online exams.
- Audit different colleges for online exams suitability.
- Create and manage separate LAN network for online exams.

Network Engineer

Orlando Academy & Solution C-DAC ACTS & Walrus Solution Pvt Ltd October 2017 to October 2018

Creating LINUX server for conducting the professional exam worked as a server administrator.

- · Handled bio metric entry, documentation and candidate crowd who came to give exam.
- Check for client PC configurations.
- Provide Training to the team for developing the server.
- Troubleshooting network related issues such as Wi-Fi and LAN connectivity
- Inventory computer, Network equipment and accessories.
- Network connectivity troubleshooting, ping, tracert, telnet.
- Configuring and troubleshooting Desktops and Laptops hardware related problems.
- Handled command center for online exam
- Attending the call of Invigilators and resolving their server related problem.

Hardware and Networking Engineer

Laxyo Energy Ltd

August 2016 to August 2017

- · Assembling & dissembling of computers.
- Installing, maintaining & troubleshooting different operating Systems.
- Installation, Configuration of Network Printer & Local Printers.
- Configuring and troubleshooting of mail clients (MS Outlook).
- Backup and Restore System Data.
- Installation, configuration and troubleshooting of operating Systems (Win7, Win8, Win8.1, Win 10, Linux)

PROFESSTIONAL COURSES:

- Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing & Switching (CCNA) from Network Bulls Gurgaon (Haryana). Cisco ID:CSC013166575 in 2017•
- Red Hat Certified System Administrator (RHCSA).Certificate Id: 180-123-929 in 2018
- Cisco Certified Network Associate Security (CCNA Security). From RST Forum Pune (MH) in 2018•

Education

Bachelor of Engineering in ELECTRONIC INSTRUMENTATION in ELECTRONIC INSTRUMENTATION engineering branch

RRMB GUJRATI SCHOOL Indore

MP Board

ST GEORAGE HIGH SCHOOL Indore

Skills / IT Skills

Certifications and Licenses

RHCSA

June 2018 to June 2021

CCNA R&S

April 2017 to April 2020

RHCE

CCNA security